A Guide to the Independent Order of St. Luke 1877-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Independent Order of St. Luke 1877-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms88-121
1.1 cubic feet, 3 boxes, 44 folders
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Right Worthy Grand Council Independent Order of St. Luke was established in 1867 by Mary Prout of Baltimore, Maryland. It was organized to "promote the general welfare of society by uniting fraternally Negro persons of good moral character who are physically, morally, and socially acceptable, to educate and assist its members in thrift, to create and maintain funds out of which members...may receive benefits for themselves or their beneficiaries, [and] to provide death benefit protection to members" (Rules and Regulations handbook, 1933).
Scope and Content Information
The bulk of the materials in the collection consist of handbooks, correspondence, receipts, programs, membership records, annual reports, and assessment reports of the Order, collected primarily from members in Blacksburg, Virginia. Also includes the minutes (1920-38) of the Blacksburg chapters of the Busy Bee and Maggie L. Walker (Secretary of the Independent Order of St. Luke) Circles.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged according to subject matter.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Independent Order of St. Luke (Blacksburg, Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.)
Contents List
- Box 1
  - 1877, 1894, 1906, 1933, n.d. (Box-folder 1-1)
    Rules and regulations handbooks.
  - 1912, 1921, 1954, 1963-68, n.d. (Box-folder 1-2)
    Receipts, cancelled chacks, and bank statements.
  - 1915-1916 (Box-folder 1-3)
    Honor Roll: Councils That Have Added Ten New Members.
  - 1916-1928 (Box-folder 1-4)
    Correspondence.
  - 1916-18, 1963-64 (Box-folder 1-5)
    Checkbooks and stubs.
  - 1919-23, 1941, 1949, 1969, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
    Miscellaneous.
  - 1920s, 1939, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s (Box-folder 1-7)
    Postcards (receipts).
  - 1920-38 (Box-folder 1-8)
    Minutes of the Blacksburg Busy Bee and Maggie L. Walker Circles.
  - 1921-23 (Box-folder 1-9)
    Death claims paid booklet.
  - 1921, 1923 (Box-folder 1-10)
    Financial report.
  - 1921-34 (Box-folder 1-11)
    Doctors' excuses.
  - 1923, 1927 (Box-folder 1-12)
    Convention souvenir programs.
  - 1923-37 (Box-folder 1-13)
    Membership payment records.
  - 1924 (Box-folder 1-14)
    Regalia catalog.
- Box 2
  - 1925-38, 1965-67 (Box-folder 2-1)
    Bank statements.
  - 1927, 1934, 1963-68 (Box-folder 2-2)
    Returned checks.
  - 1928-29, n.d. (Box-folder 2-3)
    Monthly Report sheets.
  - 1930, 1936, n.d. (Box-folder 2-4)
    Excuses for absences.
  - 1931-49 (Box-folder 2-5)
    Correspondence (including correspondence to Annie Scott).
  - 1931, 1960, 1964 (Box-folder 2-6)
    "Fraternal Monitor."
  - 1933 (Box-folder 2-7)
    By-laws.
  - 1935 (Box-folder 2-8)
    Annual report.
  - 1940 (Box-folder 2-9)
    Proof of death instructions.
  - 1943, 1953, 1955, 1956, 1958 (Box-folder 2-10)
    Lapse reports.
  - 1946-50, 1960-63 (Box-folder 2-11)
    Empty envelopes (correspondence to Annie Scott and Christine Price).
  - 1947-1958 (Box-folder 2-12)
    "Fraternal Bulletin."
  - 1950, 1951, 1964, 1965, 1966 (Box-folder 2-13)
    VPI electric bill receipts.
  - 1950-69 (Box-folder 2-14)
    Correspondence (to Annie Scott through 1963; to Christine Price, 1964-69).
  - 1950 (Box-folder 2-15)
    Phone bill.
  - 1962-67 (Box-folder 2-16)
    "Dunne's Report" pamphlets.
  - 1959-60 (Box-folder 2-17)
    Annual statement.
  - 1962, n.d. (Box-folder 2-18)
    Meeting minutes.
  - 1967 (Box-folder 2-19)
    Centennial calendar (1867-1967)
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-20)
    Price lists.
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-21)
    Applications for transfer.
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-22)
    Representatives certificate.
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-23)
    Special dispensation blank forms.
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-24)
    Legal division form.
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-25)
    Legal reserve division (blank applications).
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-26)
    Notice of death forms (blank).
  - n.d. (Box-folder 2-27)
    Juvenile department application forms (blank).
- Box 3 (Oversize)
  - 1936-1963 (Box-folder 3-1)
    Assessment reports.
  - 1937-1963 (Box-folder 3-2)
    Semi-annual tax reports.
  - 1964-1970 (Box-folder 3-3)